# KENNETH PADDEN

E: kepadden@gmail.com

P: (925) 785-0423

A: 27 Ramona Rd, Danville, CA 94526 linkedin.com/in/kenny-padden-a64329170

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Four year varsity student-athlete at the University of California, San Diego with a foundation in neuroanatomy, linguistics, data science, and cognitive analysis of humans and their communication with machines and one other. Experienced in iterative product development, personal management, and team leadership positively impacting team morale and productivity. Track record of guiding team performance as a student-athlete with a committed work ethic delivering quality and exceeding goals. Seeking high impact work in product management post graduation in June 2020.

#### WORK HISTORY

Verizon Media - *Intern II, Technical* Sunnyvale, CA • 07/2019 - Current

Worked on requirement gathering and UX improvements for Platforms Design and Identity Teams to create solutions for major features that touch millions of daily active users.

- · Product driving as a user advocate
- Modified password change flow across all properties increasing conversion rates and security
- Redesigned Yahoo Member Center focused on account health
- Developed additional logic for obfuscation of email recovery channels ensuring similar IDs are not masked in the same way
- Built out options for contextual ad placement within Identity flows
- Conducted internal audits of design and engineering providing insight into overlapping attributes and best practices across designerengineer relationships

Oath - *Intern I, Technical* Sunnyvale, CA • 07/2018 - 08/2018

Worked with Platforms Design and Machine Learning Teams leveraging Machine Learning as a Service.

- Created the label CaraML: Completely Automated Research and Machine Learning, "Making Machine Learning sweeter"
- Conducted interviews with stakeholders, current and potential users to shape the scope and overall design of the product
- Iterated on information architecture and design increasing usability and collaboration between Product Managers, Data Scientists, and Engineers

Oakland Strokes Inc - *Summer Camp Learn-to-Row Coach* Oakland, CA • 06/2015 - 08/2017

- Explored creative ways to explain fundamentals and technical feedback to beginner athletes
- Engaged young athletes creating an active, fun, and educational environment to learn the pillars of the world's greatest team sport

#### SKILLS

- · Internal tool design and development
- · User-facing product design
- Technical literacy in OOP languages: Python, Java, C, C++, C#, html, and CSS
- Experienced with data collection, cleaning, manipulation, and analysis using Kaggle datasets and Jupyter Notebooks
- Team player with strong collaboration skills

## EDUCATION

University of California - San Diego La Jolla, CA • Expected in 06/2020

Bachelor of Science: Cognitive Science

- Specialization in Design and Interaction (HCI)
- Coursework includes Neuroscience, Computer Science, Linguistics, and Psychology
- Active member of the UCSD Athletics Advanced Leadership Roundtable

# | AWARDS

- Two time Team Captain UCSD Men's Rowing 2018-20
- Recipient UCSD Athletics Scholar-Athlete Scholarship
- Recipient Oakland Strokes Coaches' Award 2016
- BSA Eagle Scout 2015
- Two time elected representative Order of the Arrow (Scouting's National Honor Society) 2014-16
- Two time Team Captain Monte Vista High School Cross Country 2012-14

#### HOBBIES

- Three end to end auto restoration projects
- Technical problem solving included full mechanical, electrical, suspension, and interior/exterior restoration
- Other requirements were budget planning, time resource management, and task prioritization
- Outdoor enthusiast